Task number nine in auto tool.
It has a class diagram and an object diagram.
And we have to do the mapping; we have to
find out x, y, and z, which one of these corresponds
to which one of these a, b, and c. So, first
I'm going to create a class diagram.
Now I'm going to create the object
diagram, and it should give us the solution,
we should find out what corresponds to what
while we're creating the object diagram.
I'm going to add three instances of B, and
it's going to ask to link to an instance of
A. Why?
It's because of this multiplicity, so the
composition here has the multiplicity one.
So, every B has to connect with an A. But
I'm going to ignore this.
Why?
Because XModeler, because the software does
not allow me, unfortunately, to create a C.
So, this c here can be satisfied.
If I link a B with
a D or a C, not just an explicit A, but I should be able to
use a D or a C instead.
just a general A, but I should be able to
But in this software, it's going to give me
the only option, which is creating an A, which
is not what I want.
So I'm going to ignore this issue.
I'm going to do two more instances here.
And also ignore the issue.
Now we're going to create this C. So, add
an instance of C. Put it here.
And C requires the link to an instance of
B at level zero.
So, it needs to connect to a B.
We have three Bs here.
So, if I choose one of them, let's say B one,
I click OK.
It linked using a b. So, it tried to fulfill
this one here.
And now it says C requires a B; let's choose
B one.
Again, let's click OK; it got linked again.
But this time, I wish I could show you, this
time it linked with an a. So, let's try again,
let's link with B one.
We click OK.
It does not work.
So, why? Because it says the link already exists.
There's not much more to do here.
So, I'm going to continue with the requirements
of C; let's do b and click OK.
And it links with an a. Let's do, this is
the old request here.
So, I'm going to ignore it.
And C is fine now.
So, C does not need anything anymore.
I'm going to continue trying to satisfy this
request here.
By connecting manually, not double-clicking
here.
I'm going to connect manually from B three
to C since every C is an A, and I'm going
to do, okay, let's just click OK.
It does not work.
So, I tried to create a link, an association
b, and it said the multiplicity does not allow
new link, and this is because of this.
So, a C is a D, and every D can connect or
has to connect with exactly one B through
this association or this aggregation b, and
it is already here.
So, if you try to connect using another aggregation
be like you try to do b connection here.
It's not going to work because this contradicts
with the multiplicity.
So, let's do again.
Let me ignore this and this link manually.
The standard is gone.
Let's go to, let's do a, we click on OK, click
anywhere to update, and we have a. So, if
you take a look here, we have y, y, y.
And here we have a, a, a.
We have one B here.
And as you saw a few seconds ago, we could
not add any more Bs.
So, this means we already know a big part of
the solution; we know that y corresponds to
a, and z corresponds to b. And now, I'm going
to do the last one here, which is this x.
Let's connect C to itself.
It gets recognized; it accepts.
So, the XModeler software allows me to connect
C to itself.
And I suspect it gets recognized exactly what
it is.
So it says it has the label of the association
here.
But I could not, I just could not find a
way to show it.
It's going to stay hidden behind this.
But this is fine.
We go to check what this is by doing more
links to something of the same type, which
is C. So, I'm going to create a temporary
instance of C. Let's call it C temp, C temp1,
actually, let's do it of type C; put it here.
And C requires whatever; just forget about
it.
And let's connect it manually to this
C. Let's ignore the rest of the things.
Okay.
So, it recognizes this link as c. How do we
check that the first one was already c and
that now we have two times c, we have two
Cs; how do you check?
Well, the connection, the association c here
has the maximum of two.
This means if you try to connect this instance
of C with another— with a third C, it should
not work.
Let me create another instance, let's call
it C temp2 or type C, let's put it here, ignore
this and then connect it, link it manually
like this.
Ignore the rest of the issues.
Let me do this again.
So, from this C, we have two arrows going
out.
So, let's pay attention to the direction.
One arrow going to C itself and one arrow
going to temporarily C number one, let's
do a third arrow, third link going from C
to C temporary.
Number two, and it says the multiplicity does
not allow a new link.
So, that is a proof that this one is a c; it
gets recognized as a c. And what happened
a few seconds ago that I somehow could link
more than two Cs together was because of
the direction of the association.
So, let's do this again.
So, if I do from C to C temp, that would be
a third outgoing arrow.
And that's not good.
That's not acceptable because of the multiplicity.
And if I do the other way around from temporary
to C it works because now C temp2 is
fine; like it still has less than two, it
has two outgoing arrows from it going to
something of type A. Now we can safely remove
these.
We don't need them anymore.
And here we are— we have a solution.
So, the solution is z is b, y is a and x is
c.